Adventure begins with a Z.
The Legend of Zorro is a action, adventure, western
film directed by Martin Campbell.
Despite trying to keep his swashbuckling to a minimum, a threat to California's pending statehood
causes the adventure-loving Don Alejandro de la Vega and his wife, Elena, to take action.
Don Alejandro de la Vega / Zorro, played by Antonio Banderas.
Elena, played by Catherine Zeta-Jones.
Joaquin, played by Adrian Alonso.
Frey Felipe, played by Julio Oscar Mechoso.
Jacob McGivens, played by Nick Chinlund.
Lupe, played by Alexa Benedetti.
The Legend of Zorro is a 2005 American Western swashbuckler film
directed by Martin Campbell, produced by Walter F.
Parkes, Laurie MacDonald and Lloyd Phillips, with music by James
Horner, and written by Roberto Orci and Alex Kurtzman.
It is the sequel to 1998's The Mask of Zorro; Antonio Banderas and Catherine Zeta-Jones reprise their roles as
the titular hero and his spouse, Elena, and Rufus Sewell stars as the villain, Count Armand.
The film takes place in San Mateo County, California and was shot in San Luis
Potosí, Mexico, with second-unit photography in Wellington, New Zealand.
The film was theatrically released on October 28, 2005, by Columbia Pictures (instead of TriStar
due to Columbia holding the sequel rights to TriStar's pre-1999 film library).
The Legend of Zorro earned $142.4 million on a $75 million budget.
It received poor reviews, with critics generally praising its acting, but
criticizing the screenplay, special effects, tone and humor.
The film explores themes of california, hero, mexico,
parent child relationship, marriage crisis.